# Abraham Aguirre

Plantation. FL | 305.338.4316 | contact@abrahamaguirre.com

Website: https://www.abrahamaguirre.com

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/aaguirre">https://github.com/aaguirre</a>7

#### Software engineer with systems and datacenter background.

I am a Team Player with strong oral and written communication skills and an analytical and problem-solving aptitude. Have background deploying hardware as a service and multiple Linux nodes in CentOS. Some experience with Kubernetes and Docker in production and in my home lab. AWS certified and taken many RedHat curses for ansible and the RedHat certified engineer certification. Have built and managed multiple websites and build apps using the MERN stack. Familiar and experience using agile methodologies and working in teams. Always learning new technologies and updating my current set.

### Experience

#### DATACENTER ENGINEER | SERVICENOW | 02/2021 - PRESENT

- Deploy new racks in the Datacenter.
- Perform Audits for inventories.
- Receive shipments.
- Write documentation.
- Federal adjudicated position.

#### DATACENTER ENGINEER | RIOT GAMES | 01/2019 - 02/2021

- Deployed Dell Open manage using AWS worldwide to cover the fleet of Dell servers servicing RIOT in its Datacenters.
- Deployed Game servers for the Latin American Region using Puppet and Jenkins.
- Helped deploy Juniper network gear using ansible playbooks.
- Coded Scripts to help with inventories and updating platforms.
- Wrote documentation for procedures and new system implementation.
- Helped add new nodes to Prometheus for monitoring.

#### DEVOPS HOME LAB | HOME | 01/2019 - PRESENT

- Currently running Rancher orchestration for Kubernetes, with some ansible playbooks to create, delete and update instances.
- Running a webserver, MySQL, Node, mongo dB and a couple of home services (plex, Minecraft, storage service, DNS, Unifi server and Dell open manage)
- This is a metal lab with Dell servers and juniper network gear.
- Cloud lab in AWS not active but ran DNS server for websites, VPN server, NODE apps and a couple of S3 storages.

#### GITHUB REPO| GITHUB | 01/2021 - PRESENT

- Mostly JavaScript projects using MERN stack.
- Some HMTL sites.
- And a couple of python projects.

## **Education**

## COMPUTER SCIENCE | 2011 | FLORIDA INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY

• Major: Computer Science

## FULL STACK ENGINEER | 2022 | UNIVERSITY OF FLORIDA

MERN Stack

## References upon request.

To learn more about me visit <a href="https://www.abrahamaguirre.com">https://www.abrahamaguirre.com</a>